<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on MarioPinedaBlog</title>
    <link>https://soyMarioPineda.github.io/Mariodoblep_Blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on MarioPinedaBlog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://soyMarioPineda.github.io/Mariodoblep_Blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://soyMarioPineda.github.io/Mariodoblep_Blog/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://soyMarioPineda.github.io/Mariodoblep_Blog/pages/about/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is &lt;strong&gt;Mario Pineda Pineda&lt;/strong&gt;, a student of Computer Engineering. My education and curiosity have led me to explore diverse disciplines such as economics, programming, psychology, music, and gastronomy. Since discovering computer science, I have observed that &lt;strong&gt;programming&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;blockchain technology&lt;/strong&gt; act as catalysts to unite these interests and create projects that impact and solve real problems. I am a firm advocate for free information and freedom of expression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on Blockchain in Mexico (test)</title>
      <link>https://soyMarioPineda.github.io/Mariodoblep_Blog/posts/prueba_post_en/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://soyMarioPineda.github.io/Mariodoblep_Blog/posts/prueba_post_en/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt; technology is no longer just a buzzword in the financial world — it has become a real opportunity for transformation in countries like Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the economic, social, and political challenges we face, the potential of &lt;strong&gt;blockchain as a driver of transparency, financial inclusion, and decentralization&lt;/strong&gt; is immense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-opportunity-to-rebuild-trust&#34;&gt;An opportunity to rebuild trust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico is a country with a history marked by corruption and institutional distrust. In this context, blockchain can serve as an immutable and verifiable ledger to reduce the manipulation of public data, government tenders, electoral processes, or social subsidies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
